人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：Iz    红豆包    奈奈良
校对：Iz          总监   IZ
时间轴：吉吉        后期：吉吉
《开心汉堡店》
第三季第十集
*洗盘盘*
*Dish-a-dee-do*
*洗盘盘  刷碗碗*
*Dish-a-de-dee, da-da-washin' the dishes*
*啦啦啦*
*Aba-ba-ba-ba.*
好啦  洗完收工
All right, all done with the dishes.
今晚是家庭游戏之夜
Time for family game night.
左手按红色
Left hand red.
我要摔倒了
I'm losing my balance.
鲍勃  孩子们
Bob? Kids?
大家都去哪儿了  怎么回事
Where is everyone? What's up?
看招  接招
Take that. And that.
你这淘气的巫婆
You naughty witch.
怎  怎么回事
What's, uh... what's going on?
我们正和老爸玩呢
It's this thing we do with Dad.
游戏的名字叫做"用石头砸女巫"
It's called "Stone the witch."
父亲是女巫  但只是假扮的
Dad's the witch, but it's just pretend.
对吗  老爸
Right, Dad?
如你们所知  今晚是家庭游戏之夜
Well, as you know, it's family game night
客厅里万事俱备了
and things are really heating up in the living room,
你们懂的
so, you know...
走吧  孩子们
Come on, kids.
我感觉全身柔软得很
I feel limber.
我准备好大展身手了
I'm ready to dominate.
-那个改天再玩如何  -让我起来
- Um, how about a rain check on that? - Let me up.
这个游戏正玩一半呢
We're kind of in the middle of something here.
那我跟你们一起玩好了
Well, then I'll just play this with you guys.
给你盖上毯子
Whoa, ooh, here comes the blanket.
热死你
That'll warm you to death.
这本目录怎么样
And, oh, ooh... how about this catalog?
让你一网打尽本季最新款运动夹克
You can learn all about the season's new blazers.
等等  我看不懂了
Wait, I'm lost.
好吧  我们休息一下
Okay, let's take five, everybody.
什么  不行  这个小桌巾如何
What? No, hey, ooh, how about doilies?
戴小饰巾的巫婆可讨人喜欢了
We can have a fancy witch with a doily hat.
妈妈  游戏结束了
Hmm. Mom, it's over.
你把它毁了  满意了吗
You ruined it, okay?
你把一切都搞砸了
You "Mommed" it all up.
你这是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
你老爸也在  他怎么就没搞砸
Dad's here... Did he "Dad" it all up?
他搞砸也是好事
Yeah, but that's a good thing.
-老天  -好吧
- Oh, boy. - Fine!
我本来也不想玩这种老掉牙的蠢游戏
I don't want to play your dumb old game anyway.
那是因为你不会玩
Well, that's 'cause you suck at it.
-天哪  -不准用这种语气和我说话
- Oh, God. - Don't you talk
你这自作聪明的大嘴巴小姐
to me that way, Miss Smart Mouth.
你刚刚给自己买了一张回房间的票
You just bought yourself a ticket to your room.
很好   这是我花钱花得最爽的一次
Oh, fine. Best money I ever spent.
在那你就没办法搞破坏了
You can't ruin anything in there.
我自己去参加家庭游戏之夜
I'm going back to family game night by myself!
我能看看吗  我穿这身会很帅
May I? I'd look great in that.
穿这身也不错
I'd look great in that.
这身也很好看
右腿踩蓝色  太棒了  我赢了
Right foot blue. Terrific, I win.
琳  你还好吗
Lin, you okay?
你没生气吧
You're not mad, are you?
-没有  没有  -好吧  晚安
- No, no. - Okay, well, good night.
你是不是觉得自己有趣极了
Oh, you just think you're so much fun.
幽默汉堡先生
Don't you, Mr. Fun Buns?
-啥  -抱歉
- What? - I'm sorry.
都怪露易丝
It's just that Louise.
她一直都更喜欢你
She's always liked you better.
从婴儿时代起她就这样
Ever since she was a baby.
你是不是妈咪的小宝贝啊
Are you Mommy's little girl?
爸爸
Dada.
还有妈妈
And Mama.
爸爸
Dada.
-妈妈  -爸爸
- Mama. - Dada.
爸爸
Dada.
-妈妈  -爸爸
- Mama. - Dada.
-妈...妈  -爸...爸
- M... Ma... - Da... Da...
-妈妈妈妈  -爸爸爸爸
- Ma. Ma. Ma. - Da. Da. Da.
-爸爸爸爸  -妈妈妈妈  够了
- Da, da, da! - Ma... ma! All right, you know what?
你自己换尿布吧
Change your own diaper.
别担心  琳
Well, don't worry, Lin.
她只是在经历一个阶段
She's just going through a phase.
九岁这个阶段  她会好起来的
A nine-year phase... she'll grow out of it.
我可等不了了
Well, I'm not waiting for that.
"妈妈帮"上面写说
According to the Phenomimom...
"妈妈帮"
The Phenomimom?
这是达科塔・鲍姆写给妈妈们的博客
It's a mommy blog, by Dakota Applebaum.
她说母亲和女儿沟通的一个办法
She says one way mothers and daughters connect
就是讲故事
is through story time.
"妈妈帮"  这名字念起来挺好玩
Phenomimom... that's fun to say.
我要去给那个小屁孩讲讲故事
I am gonna go story that little punk.
听起来不错
Sounds good.
露易丝  你睡着了吗  宝贝
Louise, you awake, baby?
露易丝
Louise?
Louise!
怎么了  发生什么事了
What? What's going on?
抱歉  我吵醒你了吗
Sorry. Did I wake you up?
看看我带了什么
Look what I brought.
鸽趾公主  还记得吗
Princess Pigeon Toe... remember?
不要
Oh, no.
-拜托别讲那个  -挪一挪
- Not that book. - Scootch over.
挪一挪
Scootch.
-这是单人床  -往那边点
- This is a twin. - Come on.
这儿没多大地方
There's not a lot of room.
快点  快点  挪挪  挪挪
Come on, come on. Move, move, move.
"鸽趾公主住在企鹅巷的孔雀城堡里"
"Princess Pigeon Toe lived in a peacock castle on Penguin Lane."
请别讲了  请别讲了  请别讲了
Please stop, please stop, please stop.
"每天  她都去鹦鹉公园
"Every day, she went to Parakeet Park
和海豚宝利玩纸牌游戏"
to play pinochle with Pauly the Porpoise."
不要  拜托  让我睡觉
Oh, no! Please, just let me sleep!
"有时它们会带野餐篮  装满了咸菜
"Sometimes they take a picnic basket full of pickles
-还有辣椒和南瓜饼"  -拜托别讲了
and peppers and pumpkin pie!" - Please make it stop!
-是克莱尔和杰奎琳  -谁
- It's Claire and Jacqueline. - Who?
学校里最受欢迎的女孩
The most popular girls at school.
-我看上去怎么样  -还不错
- How do I look? - Oh, good...
嗨  我是蒂娜  今天由我为你们点餐
Hi. I'm Tina. I'll be your server today,
希望未来我能成为你们的好朋友
and hopefully in the future, your good friend.
很好  我要一个芝士汉堡
That's nice. I'll have a cheeseburger.
我也是
Me, too.
好的  两个芝士汉堡
Okay, two cheeseburgers...
克莱尔  你见瑞秋的腿了没
Claire, did you see Rachel's legs?
全是毛
They are so hairy.
天哪  我知道  太恶心了
Oh, my God, I know... so gross.
对吧  我拜托她去买把剃刀
Right? Get a razor, girl.
我看她得买割草机才行
More like a lawnmower.
你们什么时候长出来的
When did you get there?
-你说什么  -没什么
- What'd you say? - Nothing.
-吉恩  藏住我的腿  -包在我身上
- Gene, hide my legs. - On it!
没什么好看的
Nothing to see here.
我们餐饮界的人都是这么走路的
This is just how we walk in the restaurant biz.
我的小蒂娜长大了
My teeny Tina's growing up.
都开始长腿毛了呢
With her little leg hairs.
只需要剃到膝盖那边就好了
Just shave up to the knee.
脱衣舞女才剃膝盖以上的部分
Only strippers shave above the knee.
-至少称职的脱衣舞女是这样  -好吧
- The good ones anyway. - Okay.
-谁做的这玩意  -我做的
- Um... who did this? - I did.
原来是你做的
Oh, you did?
-没错  -真是惊喜啊
- Yes. - Oh, what a surprise.
你把它落我房间里了
Well, you left it in my room.
是的  "妈妈帮"...
Yeah, the Phenomi...
我是说  我认为很有必要
I mean, I think it's important
把我们的感情具体化为摸得着的东西
to create tangible expressions of our relationship.
那不是  哎哟
Oh, well, isn't that... Whoops.
把它挂到你房间里去
Hey, you hang that up in your room.
要知道你早晚有一天会用到你老妈
You know you're gonna need your mother someday.
到时谁帮你刮腿毛
Who's gonna shave your legs, huh?
没人  我要让腿毛长得又长又糙
No one... I'm gonna grow them out all long and scraggily.
我要让双腿长成两颗风滚草
I want to look like a torso on two tumbleweeds.
我还要从电视里学习滚床单
And I'm gonna learn about sex from television,
所以连这个我都不必从你那学习
so I don't need that from you, either!
等等  也许你应该先平复下心情
Wait, maybe you should take some time to cool off.
没错  生气时可不该刮腿毛
Yeah, I don't think you should shave angry.
谁生气了
Who's angry?
听着  琳
Uh, listen, Lin,
你不觉得自己有点太强硬了吗
do you think you might be forcing it a little?
-我没有  鲍勃  -好吧
- I'm not forcing it, Bob! - Right.
露易丝会明白她最好的朋友就是她妈咪
Louise is gonna see that her best friend is her mommy
这思想我硬灌也要灌进她脑瓜里
even if I have to shake it into her.
-灌进去  灌进去  -住手  住手
- Shake it. Yes. Shake it. - Stop. No. Stop.
就像那样
Like that.
看哪
Ooh, look.
-不  -就是它了
- No. - Yes.
-不  不  不  不  -就要
- No, no, no, no. - Yes!
好咧  我们上路了
Okay, here we go.
只是让你陪我去办点事  没别的意思
Going on a little errand, that's all.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
听着  我认为我们应该分开一段时间
Look, I think we should spend some time apart.
是么
Mm-hmm, yeah.
我目前还没有
I'm just not really looking
要定下来的打算
for something serious right now.
当然  当然  亲爱的
Sure, sure, honey.
你懂的  我的意思是...
You understand... I mean, yeah,
虽然会有些尴尬
it's gonna be a little awkward.
你还有东西放在我那边
You got some of your stuff at my place.
-我们还住一起  -我们到咯
- We live together... - We're here!
激光枪战  是有点过时  不过还好啦
Laser tag... A little dated, but all right.
不是那个
Not that.
是那个
That!
教养中心  全天开放
母女感情修复课程
我被绑架了
I've been kidnapped!
不  她没有  没事
No, she hasn't. We're fine.
赶紧走吧  没什么好看的
Keep moving. Nothing to see here.
衬衣不错
Nice blouse.
教 养 中 心
-来吧  -不  不  不  不
- Come on. - No, no, no, no, no!
露易丝  别紧张
Louise, relax.
我又不是在虐待你
It's not like I'm torturing you.
我只是想让你跟我去参加一个
I'm just taking you to an eight-hour
8小时的母女感情修复课程
mother/daughter seminar.
8小时
Eight hours?!
没错  我们需要帮助
Yes, our relationship needs help.
专业的帮助
Professional help.
快启动  妈的  启动呀
Start, damn you, start.
-不要  -好吧  好吧
- No! - Oh, all right, all right.
-20块  -啥
- 20 bucks. - What?
你如果跟我参加这个课程
I'll give you 20 bucks
我就给你20块
if you come and do this with me.
有意思  1000块
Interesting... $1,000.
-28  -29块5
- $28. - $29.50.
-成交  -这将是我
- Deal. -This is gonna be the hardest money
挣得最辛苦的一笔钱
I've ever earned.
除非你以后做妓女
Unless you become a hooker.
启迪时间
欢迎大家
Welcome, everyone.
欢迎来到我的母女情感修复课程
Welcome to my mother/daughter seminar...
启迪时间
Modo Time.
我是达科塔
I'm Dakota.
你就是写"妈妈帮"的人
You're the Phenomimom?
可你是男的啊
But you're a man.
我的确是男的
I am a man.
不过没关系
And that's okay.
女性的精神在我们每个人身体里流淌
The female spirit flows through all of us.
我们都是浑身充满雌激素的隐忍者
We're all estro-geniuses.
大家站起来跟我说
Everybody stand up and say it,
"我是浑身充满雌激素的隐忍者"
"I am an estro-genius."
我是浑身充满雌激素的隐忍者
I am an estro-genius.
天哪
Oh, dear.
各位  今天我们要回到过去
Guys, today we are going back.
回到母亲的子宫里
We're gonna go all the way back to the womb.
我们要举行一场回宫仪式
We're gonna get into a womb-a-tism!
-一场啥  -回宫仪式
- A what? - A womb-a-tism!
啥
Ooh, a what?
不要
No.
抱歉  我们迟到了
Hi. Sorry we're late.
来了个男孩儿
Ooh, a male daughter.
是洛根你呀
Ha-ha, Logan.
我去  怎么是这种地方
Oh, God, it's here.
子宫屋
抱歉  只剩这个课程了
Sorry, this was the only seminar available,
我们昨天吵了一架
and we had an incident yesterday.
洛根对我说了那个"婊"字开头的词
Logan called me the "B" Word.
这种词语根本就不该存在
Why must that word exist?
提问
Question.
"子宫屋"是啥
What's the "Uter-room"?
我希望我们
Well, I'm hoping what's in that room
不会用到那个房间
won't be necessary.
现在  开始我们的启迪时间把
Now, let Modo Time begin!
老爸  你能不能搁下手上的活
Dad, I want you to drop everything you're doing
帮我脱个毛
and shave my legs.
我来"搁"
I'll take care of the first part.
-吉恩  -我是在帮忙
- Gene. - I was trying to help.
蒂娜  你就不能自己剃吗
Uh, Tina, can't you just shave them yourself?
我试过了
I tried.
我的天
Oh, God!
-天哪  -上帝
- Oh, oh, dear. - Oh... oh, my... aah!
你先别剃了  等你老妈回来吧
No more razors for you. Just wait for Mom.
要等你自己等去吧  如果我现在不剃
You wait for Mom. If I don't shave this before school tomorrow,
明天克莱尔和杰奎琳
Claire and Jacqueline
在某个餐馆里嘲笑的人可能就是我了
might talk about me at some restaurant.
-好吧  -也许是在海鲜餐厅
- All right, fine. - Like a seafood restaurant
-或者中餐馆  -蒂娜
- or a Chinese restaurant. - Tina.
或是那个用丛林音效做背景音乐的
Or that rain forest restaurant
雨林餐厅
with all the jungle sounds.
美国海鲜餐厅连锁
或者是麦考密特和施密特餐厅
Or McCormick and Schmidt's.
我说我帮你脱
I said I'll do it.
好的  谢谢
Oh, okay, thanks.
曾几何时  你们存活所需的一切养分
There was a time when you got all you needed
都来自母亲的脐带
from your mother through a single cord.
妈妈们  请把脐带模具
Mothers, please strap your symbolic umbilical cords
绑到你女儿的脸上
to your daughters' faces.
我把它称为"脐模"
I call them "Umbilitators".
脐带才不是这么工作的
That's not how umbilical cords work.
来吧
Here we go!
这根本就是胡扯
It doesn't make any sense.
给你们的胎儿喂食吧
And feed those fetuses.
来一口
Down the hatch.
露易丝  张嘴
Louise, open your mouth.
她没事  我们进行得很好
Yeah, she's fine. We're fine.
快点给我张嘴  你这胚胎
Yes, open that fetus mouth!
好好玩哦
Oh, it's fun.
-钱  -啥
- Money. - What?
钱  别想再敲诈我
Money, no... no more extorting me.
好吧
Okay, fine.
五块  给我吞下去
Five bucks... now, swallow.
她可喜欢了
Mmm, oh, she loves it.
脱毛中心
你好
Oh, hello.
你是来脱背毛的吧
You must be here for our back waxing special.
不是
Um, no.
臂毛么
Arm waxing?
-不是  -难道是阴毛
- No. - Scrotal waxing?
-不  啥  不是  -没错  就是那个
- No... What? No! Yeah, that one.
-不  不  不是那个  -就是
- No, no, not that one. - Yes.
-吉恩  住嘴  -你需要的
- Gene, stop. - You need it.
吉恩  闭嘴  是我的女儿
Gene, shut up. My daughter needs
-她来脱腿毛  -是我
- to get her legs waxed. - Hi.
虚惊一场
Oh. Phew.
不是我不想帮你脱
I mean, not that I don't want to wax you...
不过  我也有尺度的
but no, I have my limits.
你说话没必要这么伤人的
Okay, well, you don't have to be rude.
我们到里面去吧  亲爱的
Why don't we just take you in the back, sweetheart?
那是你该做的
It's your job, you know.
我愿意帮你脱毛  老爸
I'd wax you, Dad.
谢了  吉恩
Thanks, Gene.
出生的时候到了
Time to be born.
真恶心
This is disgusting.
你说话口气和你老爸一模一样
You sound just like your father.
露易丝  快到妈妈这儿来
Louise, come to Mama.
不必了  我在这儿挺好  谢谢
Oh, no, I think I'm good, thank you.
我能用下剪刀吗  达科塔
Can I get some scissors, Dakota?
来个剖腹产
Do a little C-section?
这袋子花了我50块  所以  不行
Those vagisacks cost $50, so... no.
说到钱
Speaking of money.
拿去
Here.
有人要出来咯
Someone's dilating.
她出来啦
There she is.
现在请把宝宝包起来
And time to swaddle the baby.
不  不  不  不  不  天呐
No, no, no, no, no, no, no... oh, God.
把它裹起来  裹起来
Snug it up, now, snug it up.
不
No.
那边我剃过了
I shaved that part.
看来你意志很坚决嘛
You must have been very determined.
谢谢你
Thank you.
好了  流程是这样的
Okay, here's what we're gonna do.
我会先把热蜡涂在你的腿上
We're gonna put the hot wax on your legs.
然后再把这些布条放在上面
And then we put these strips on your legs
使劲一撕
and pull them off.
会有一丁点疼
And it kind of hurts.
其实挺疼的
A lot.
老爸
Dad!
我不知道我能否坚持下来
I don't know if I can do this.
老爸  你得陪我一起做
Dad, you have to do it with me.
什么  不  不可能
What? No, no way.
可以的  就像那次你为了证明给我看
Yes, it's like when you got that flu shot
打流感疫苗不疼一样
to show me it was okay.
对  我那次很勇敢  可是...
Yeah, that was brave of me, but...
求你了
Please?
我其实没有我表现的那么坚强
I know I act tough, but I'm not.
我的天  我最怕别人哭了
Oh, my God... the crying.
好吧  我做就是了
Okay, I'll do it.
好耶  剃阴毛
Yay, scrotal wax.
不  吉恩  不是阴毛  腿毛
No, Gene, not scrotal, just leg.
好了  各位  角色互换环节
Okay, everybody, role reversal.
露易丝  你现在就是琳达了
Louise, you're Linda now.
你要让你目中无人的女儿露易丝
And you're trying to get your defiant daughter Louise
收拾她的房间
to clean her room.
开始
Action.
角色扮演你可得大出血了
Role play's gonna cost you big.
表现好你才有的拿
I'll pay for it when I see it.
大家好  我是琳达
Hello. I'm Linda.
*我要你收拾自己的房间*
*And I want you to clean your room*
*所以唱了这首歌*
*So I'm singing this song.*
*可我偏不收*
*But I'm not gonna clean my room.*
-不不不不  你别唱  -怎么
- No-no-no-no. No singing. - Wha...?
我扮演你  所以才唱歌
I'm doing you. That's why I'm singing.
而你扮演我  用不着唱歌
You're doing me, so you don't sing.
我就是要唱怎么着
Oh, like I'm not gonna sing!
-你最好赶紧收拾房间  -我才不干呢
- Oh, you better clean your room. - I will never clean my room
-因为我唱歌了  -因为我就这么叛逆
- 'Cause I'm singing this song. - 'Cause I'm so rebellious!
-你快去收拾房间  -不  我就不停
- And you're gonna clean your room! - No, I'm not gonna stop!
好了  结束了  为琳达和露易丝鼓掌
Okay, you two are done. Big hand for Linda and Louise.
请回坐吧
Please sit down.
好极了  你把它搞砸了
Great. You blew it.
我  你什么都没演出来
I blew it? You gave me nothing out there!
冲你那表现别想拿钱了
Well, nothing is what you're getting paid for that!
暂停下
Whoa. Time out.
琳达  你是用钱把女儿哄过来的吗
Linda, have you been paying your daughter to be here?
抱歉  达科塔
I'm sorry, Dakota,
可不给钱她根本不来
but it's the only way she'd do it.
我是个失败的母亲
I'm a terrible mother.
琳达  你真的真的有够失败
Oh, Linda, you really, really are.
各位  各位  听好了
Everybody, everybody, listen, okay?
琳达是个好母亲
Linda is a good mother.
因为她所作所为都是出于爱
Because she did it out of love.
因此我提名你竞选"最有价值妈妈"
And that puts you in the running for the Most Valuable Mommy award...
各位 这一奖项将于今天结束之时颁发
the MVM, everybody... which I give out at the end of the day.
好耶  最有价值妈妈
All right!  MVM!
至于你  我觉得你
And as for you, I don't feel like
根本没认真对待"启迪时间"
you're taking Modo Time seriously.
是的  完全没有
Oh, no, not at all.
这让我对你印象很差
And that makes me feel negatively towards you.
也许这样能让你看得更清楚
Well, maybe this will help clear things up.
这是你的课  你看
Here's your seminar. See it?
在我手里真是可爱又漂亮
It's so cute and nice in my hand, and...
你刚才是对我的课放屁了吗
Did you just fart on my seminar?
我也放一个
Ye, me, too!
好好  没关系
Okay, that's... that's fine.
我知道要把你们怎么办了
I think I know what we need to do here.
子宫屋
-你看着点  -放开我
- Hey! Watch it! - Get off me!
你俩就好好呆在这里
You two will stay in there until you're ready
什么时候想通什么时候出来
to engage in this experience!
差点忘了
Oh, almost forgot.
-我的天  -那是什么
- Oh, God. - What is that?
给你们循环播放《怪诞星期五》
It's Freaky Friday on a loop.
讲述母女因互换身体引发的一系列喜剧的电影
-妈  你好老  -就你年轻
- Mom, you're old. - And you're young!
我们要是互换身体会不会很疯狂
Wouldn't it be crazy if we switched bodies?
不
No...!
不要
不是吧  我们的身体竟然互换了
Oh, no, we switched bodies!
我们这是遇上什么怪事了
What a crazy journey we are on.
这电影根本毫无逻辑可言嘛
The logic of this movie is very unsettling!
你不能这么做  你这个禽兽
You can't do this, you monsters!
好了  既然你们的孩子都被锁了
All right, well, why don't you two pair up
不如你们俩组成一组
now that your children are locked away?
当然好了  达科塔  来吧  辛西娅
Of course, Dakota. Come on, Cynthia.
你和我一起学习为人母的经验吧
Let's you and me learn some mommy skills together.
非常愿意  琳达
I'd like that, Linda.
别忘了我们还要评
And don't forget about
"最有价值妈妈"哟  各位
that Most Valuable Mommy award, everybody.
很漂亮的一条绶带
It's a beautiful sash.
-那绶带是我的  -除非我死
- I want that sash. - Over my dead body.
我要定了  绶带我都爱
I want that sash. I love sashes.
我的腿好自由啊
My legs are so free.
原来腿直接和空气接触是这种感觉
Mmm. So that's what air feels like.
真好
It's nice.
没错  我裤子的布料感觉棒极了
Yeah, these pants feel incredible.
所有男的都应该去剃腿毛
Why don't all men do this?
吉恩  你怎么老发出怪声
Gene, why are you making noises?
我这是嫉妒的怒气
They're my jealousy noises!
嫉妒从何而来
What are you saying?
我也想剃腿毛
I want to wax my legs, too!
剃这两条
These ones right here!
你哪有什么腿毛
You don't even have leg hair.
跟我的心说去吧
Tell that to my heart!
好吧 我们这就掉头
Hold on, everybody. We're making a U-turn.
好啊
All right!
辛西娅  你轻点噢
Ow! Gentle touch, Cynthia.
母亲都会轻轻的
A mother's gentle touch.
真抱歉
I'm so sorry.
达科塔  我给露易丝梳头时
You know, Dakota, when I braid Louise's hair,
-总给她唱歌  -是么  唱什么
- I sing her a song. - Ah, yes, please.
*这边一缕  那边一缕*
*Here goes the hair and there goes the hair *
*哈利・杜鲁门在哪呢[美国前总统]*
*And where is Harry Truman?*
*他入土为安了  他入土为安了*
*He's dead in the ground, he's dead in the ground*
*他去了  去了  去了*
*He's dead, dead, dead...*
我们身体又换回来
Well we switched bodies again,
一切回归正常了
and everything's back to normal.
我终于理解你了  妈妈
I finally understand you, Mom.
我要被这电影感化了
Freaky Friday's getting to me, man.
他们真的理解彼此了
They really understand each other!
你给我振作起来
You pull yourself together.
我们要离开这
We got to get out of here.
他们需要的只是站在对方的角度看问题
They just had to see things from each other's perspective.
洛根  振作起来  动动脑子
Logan, come on! We got to think!
设身处地多为对方着想
Walk a mile in each other's shoes...
我发誓  你要是再嗦
Oh, I swear to God, if you keep talking,
我就打烂你的肚子
I'm gonna gut-punch you!
这是个关于爱和接纳的故事
It's a beautiful story of love and acceptance.
我的肚子
Oh, my stomach!
等等  有办法了
Wait a minute. That's it!
看到没  我说了吧
See? What'd I tell you?
真滑溜啊
That is smooth.
够了  够了  泰迪
Whoa, whoa, Teddy.
上面不给摸吗
What, a little high up on the leg?
-是的  -抱歉
- Yeah. - Sorry.
只能到膝盖
There's a stop sign right here.
-现在摸摸我的吧  -还有我的
- Now feel mine. - And mine.
不行  泰迪  不许碰他们
No, Teddy, don't touch their legs.
看看我的
Look at this.
你都能用它刷锅了
You could wash a pan with that.
也许我也该去那儿把它处理了
Hey, maybe I'll shoot over there and get what you got.
-去吧  -算了  再一想吧
- Yeah. - Nah, on second thought,
我还真舍不得这些小家伙们
I couldn't get rid of these little guys.
他们是我的好朋友小茸茸
They're my little furry friends.
别听他的  你让他丢脸了
Don't listen to him. You're an embarrassment!
别  别听他的  你很好
No, don't listen to him. You're all right.
小茸茸
Furry little... friends?
真好玩  再荡高点  蒂娜
This is fun! Higher, Tina!
再高点
Higher!
教 养 中 心
当心那只熊  又来了头美洲狮
Watch out for that bear! Whoo! Here comes a puma!
启迪时间
-妈妈  妈妈  -妈妈
- Mommy! Mommy! - Mommy!
各位  听到没
Did you hear that, everybody?
他们想通了  子宫屋起作用了
They're coming around. The Uter-Room is working!
刚从脐带给我灌的汤有问题  好疼妈妈
Oh, that umbilical soup got me, Mom. Got me real bad.
能给我揉揉肚子吗
Rub my tummy?
我也要
Mine, too.
我可怜的小宝贝
Oh, my poor baby.
太感人了
It's wonderful.
这是母亲最原始的本能释放啊
A mother's instinct at its most primal level!
快来  妈妈们  快来看看
Come, other mothers, come and see!
妈妈会让你好起来的
Mommy's gonna make you all better.
妈妈会让你好得比他快的
Well, this mommy's gonna make you all better first.
闪
Now! Ha!
-这是在搞什么  -你们在干嘛
- What the hell's going on? - Uh, what are... what are you doing?
你们中了有史以来最老掉牙的计
You fell for the oldest trick in the book.
-装肚子痛  -用肚子唬人的滥招
- The fake tummy ache! - The old belly bluff.
居然是装肚子痛
Oh, the belly bluff!
那么  就恕不奉陪了
Now, if you'll excuse us,
姐妹们
us girls...
-抱歉  女士们  -谢谢
- Sorry. Ladies... - Thank you.
我们去玩激光枪战吧
Are going to play laser tag.
我祝你的屁股被射得稀巴烂
Oh, I hope those lasers hit you right in the butt!
子宫屋
给我打开
Come on, you!
靠  都怪我的肩膀太柔弱
Damn these delicate shoulders!
放着我来
Let me try.
你从哪儿学的破门技巧的
Where'd you learn how to break down a door,
女童子军吗  起开
Girl Scout camp? Move it.
教 养 中 心
绅士镭射枪战馆
不得遮掩感光区
No covering your sensors.
不得攀爬障碍物
No climbing on the barriers.
不得有任何身体接触
And no physical contact of any kind.
同意所有"不得"
Well, agree to disagree.
我感觉把我们老妈关起来好像不太好
I feel kind of bad about locking our moms in that room.
我杀死了他们
I killed them.
我把他们全杀了
I killed them all.
蒂娜  怎  怎么了
Tina, what... what's wrong?
我把我的小茸茸杀死了
I killed my friendly leg hairs.
他们会再长出来的
Um... oh. Well, they'll grow back.
我说的不只是这个
It's not just that.
我脱毛是因为
I did it 'cause I was worried
担心那些女生的眼光
about what those girls would think of me.
我就是胆小鬼  一只被剃光了毛的羊
I'm a sheep! A hairless sheep!
因为同龄人的压力而妥协
So you gave in to peer pressure.
这是每个人都会遇到的事啊
It happens to everybody.
我是说  你知道我为啥要穿这双鞋吗
I mean, why do you think I wear these shoes?
因为你不在意外表吗
'Cause you don't care what you look like?
啥  不  因为  才不是
What? No. 'Cause I... No.
因为我看到别的厨师也在穿
'Cause I saw some other chefs wearing them
于是我就觉得这鞋不错
and I thought they were cool.
你不觉得吗
Don't you think?
当然  当然
Yeah, yeah.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我觉得...  确实  很酷
I think they're... Yeah, they're cool.
好吧  但如果你觉得他们不怎么样
Um... okay. Well, because if they don't look...
看起来很蠢的话  我就不穿了
if they look stupid, I won't wear them.
-不会  这鞋...很  -当我没说
- No, they... Yeah. - Forget it. Listen.
听着  不管有没有腿毛  你都是蒂娜
Leg hair or no leg hair, you're still Tina,
当遇到真正的大事的时候
and when it comes to the important stuff,
你会做出正确的抉择
you'll make the right choice.
吉恩  穿条裤子
Gene, put some pants on.
我不
No!
搞什么
What the hell?
你们咋出来的
How'd you get out?
我把门撞开了
I busted through the door.
是我们把门撞开了
Um, we busted through the door.
好吧  我的肩和辛西娅的左胸
Fine. My shoulder and Cynthia's left boob.
够了  各位  游戏结束了
All right, everybody. Fun's over.
我们继续我们的启迪时间吧
Now, let's get back on Modo Time.
想都别想
Oh, no freaking way!
我要你现在就给我回教养中心去
You are coming back to the Nurture Center right now!
你麻烦大了  洛根・贝里・布什
You're in big trouble, Logan Berry Bush.
洛根的全名在英语里有罗甘莓的意思
他叫罗甘莓
Logan Berry Bush?
我们取名的时候大意了  怎样
We didn't think it through.
好了  各位  冷静
Okay, everybody, calm down.
我们怎样才能下去
Now, how do we get down there?
要下去都得拿镭射枪穿背心
No one goes in without a vest and a laser gun.
这是不可能的
Well, that's not happening.
-我下去  -不  琳达
- I'll go down there! - Linda, no!
镭射枪战和我们到目前为止
Laser tag goes against
所有的努力都背道而驰
everything we've been working on.
再说了  你们是母亲啊
And besides... you're mothers.
是的  老娘的枪在哪儿
Uh-huh. Where's mommy's gun?!
欢迎参战
So, welcome to the war.
这样  我们先试试
Okay, first, uh... let's just try
看能不能谈判  然后...
to create a dialogue, and we'll...
你玩儿完了  大小姐
You're gonna get it, Miss Missy!
多开枪少说话  唠叨婆
Why don't you let your gun do the talking, blabbermouth!
你叫我唠叨婆
Blabbermouth?
琳达  我们不能这样
Linda, this isn't right!
我看好得很
Feels pretty good to me!
我现在命令你放下武器
I am ordering you to put down your gun
去抱抱你的女儿
and go cradle your daughter!
我还是射她比较好
No! I'm gonna shoot her instead!
中招了吧
Ha! Gotcha!
那枪是我让你的
I gave you that one!
你再这样下去
This is seriously hurting your chances
就别想当"最有价值母亲"了
of receiving the MVM award!
你要我把绶带给辛西娅吗
Maybe I should give the sash to Cynthia, huh?
受死吧  洛根
Die, Logan!
你说真的吗  我是"最有价值母亲"吗
Oh-whoa-whoa-whoa, seriously? I'm the MVM?
什么  我的绶带
What?! The sash! Oh!
这是报你绑架我的仇
That's for kidnapping me!
这是报你逼我去听那个变态的课的仇
And that's for taking me to The Momgina Monologues!
你差点杀了你老妈  你开心了吗
You almost killed your mother. I hope you're happy.
很开心  还有遗言吗
I am. Any last words?
有  我希望
Yes. I just wish...
我只希望你能喜欢我  就是这样
I just wish you liked me, that's all.
但我想是没可能了  动手吧
But I guess you never will, so go ahead,
结束我的痛苦吧
put me out of my misery.
你做这些都因为你认为我不喜欢你吗
Is this all 'cause you think I don't like you?
来吧  动手吧  射我吧
Go on. Just do it. Just go.
让我死  来吧
Take me out. Go ahead.
老妈  我今天的行为也许确实过火了
Mom, I guess I've been kind of a "B" Word today.
是的  但我也有点太强硬了
You have. But I came on a little strong.
对不...
I'm sorr...
你  你毁了我那么完美的课  小屁孩
You! You ruined my beautiful seminar, you little brat!
我要你付出代价
And now you're gonna pay!
不  我的孩子
No! My baby!
吃我这一枪  达科塔
Suck on this soup tube, Dakota!
镭口味的
It's laser-flavored!
老妈  干得好
Mom, nice!
正北方向  达科塔
Look north, Dakota.
老妈你真棒
Whoa, Mom, amazing!
今日舍我其谁
Make my day!
不  不  还是前面那个好一点
No, no, better before.
等等  等等  等一下
Wait, wait. Hold on.
给我从障碍物上下来
Hey, get off the equipment!
闪一边去
Oh, shove it!
我和女儿培养感情呢
I'm bonding with my daughter!
没错  我们培养感情呢
Yeah, we're bonding here!
这是有史以来最好的治疗
Best therapy ever.
你们真应该看看老妈拿下达科塔的场面
You should have seen the way Mom took down Dakota.
"妈妈帮"见鬼去吧
Phenomimom, my ass.
见鬼去吧  击掌
My ass, too! Up high!
真是我的乖女儿
Yeah, that my girl!
别抓了  你俩
Quit scratching, you two.
我忍不了  好痒
Can't help it. It itches.
我也是  要不要交换
Yeah, mine, too. Switch?
好的
Okay.
拜托  使点儿劲
Come on. Scratch like a man!
像个男人
Give it to me!
蒂娜  抱歉我没参与
Tina, I'm sorry I wasn't there
你人生第一次脱毛
to give you your first shave.
没关系  反正我也后悔了
It's okay. I regretted it anyway.
但和老爸去脱毛中心还挺开心的
But it was fun going to the waxing salon with Dad.
他叫得真大声
He's a screamer.
吉恩  太大力了
Ow, Gene! Not so hard!
-你们的经历听起来更好玩嘛  -什么
- Aw, man! Your day sounds better. - What?
我也想跟老爸去脱毛然后再后悔
I want to go shave my legs with Dad and then regret it.
好  我们明天跟老爸
Yeah, let's make all the same mistakes
去把同样的错误通通再犯一遍好了
with Dad again tomorrow!
好吧  老爸万岁
Okay. Yay, Dad.
你们都去吃屎吧
Oh, screw all of you.
别这样  老妈  来抱抱
Ah, Mom. Come here.